Things just got a little more despicable.
Despicable Me 4 is a family, comedy, animation film directed by Chris Renaud.
Gru and Lucy and their girls—Margo, Edith and Agnes—welcome a new member to
the Gru family, Gru Jr., who is intent on tormenting his dad.
Gru also faces a new nemesis in Maxime Le Mal and his femme fatale
girlfriend Valentina, forcing the family to go on the run.
Gru (voice), played by Steve Carell.
Lucy (voice), played by Kristen Wiig.
Maxime (voice), played by Will Ferrell.
Valentina (voice), played by Sofía Vergara.
Margo (voice), played by Miranda Cosgrove.
Edith (voice), played by Dana Gaier.
Despicable Me 4 is a 2024 American animated comedy film directed by
Chris Renaud and written by Mike White and Ken Daurio.
Produced by Illumination and distributed by Universal Pictures, it is the sequel to
Despicable Me 3 (2017) and the sixth film in the Despicable Me franchise.
The film stars the voices of Steve Carell, Kristen Wiig, Pierre Coffin, Joey King,
Miranda Cosgrove, Stephen Colbert, Sofía Vergara, and Will Ferrell.
The film sees reformed supervillain and secret agent Gru temporarily relocate his
family to a safe house when his old rival Maxime Le Mal seeks revenge.
Subplots deal with Gru's family adjusting to their new lives, teenage neighbor Poppy Prescott trying to follow
in Gru's footsteps, and a group of Gru's Minions becoming superheroes known as the Mega Minions.
Development on a fourth main Despicable Me film began in September 2017.
It was officially confirmed in February 2022, with Renaud, Delage, and White
attached as director, co-director, and writer, respectively.
Production was underway by June 2022.
Most of the main voice cast was announced in January 2024, with Hoffman and
Daurio revealed as co-producer and co-writer, respectively.
Heitor Pereira and Pharrell Williams returned from previous installments to
compose the score and write original songs and themes, respectively.
Despicable Me 4 debuted at the Jazz at Lincoln Center in New York on June 9,
2024, and was theatrically released in the United States on July 3.
Despite mixed reviews, the film continued the franchise's streak of box-office successes, grossing $972 million
worldwide against a budget of $100 million, making it the fourth-highest-grossing film of 2024.
The film explores themes of superhero, villain,
sequel, super villain, aftercreditsstinger.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.